<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An ordinance of the Lords &amp; Commons assembled in Parliament, for the reliefe of the distressed Protestants come out of Ireland. Die Sabbati, 28. August, 1647. Ordered by the Lords in Parliament assembled, that this ordinance be forth-with printed &amp; published. Jo: Brown Cler: Parl.</title>
            <title>Laws, etc.</title>
            <author>England and Wales.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1647</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 6 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A83248</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing E2029</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E404_39</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R201871</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99862360</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99862360</idno>
            <idno type="VID">114517</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A83248)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 114517)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 64:E404[39])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An ordinance of the Lords &amp; Commons assembled in Parliament, for the reliefe of the distressed Protestants come out of Ireland. Die Sabbati, 28. August, 1647. Ordered by the Lords in Parliament assembled, that this ordinance be forth-with printed &amp; published. Jo: Brown Cler: Parl.</title>
                  <title>Laws, etc.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales.</author>
                  <author>England and Wales. Parliament.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 5, [1] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for John Wright at the Kings head in the Olde-Baily,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London, :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1647.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Annotation on Thomason copy: "Aug: 30".</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Protestants --  Ireland --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Ireland --  History --  1625-1649 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-07</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-08</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:114517:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 67 -->
            <p>AN ORDINANCE Of the Lords &amp; Commons Aſſembled in PARLIAMENT, For the reliefe of the diſtreſſed Proteſtants come out of <hi>IRELAND.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="license">
                        <opener>
                           <dateline>
                              <date>Die Sabbati, 28. Auguſt, 1647.</date>
                           </dateline>
                        </opener>
                        <p>ORdered by the Lords in Parliament Aſſembled, that this Ordinance be forth-with Printed &amp; publiſhed.</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>Jo: Brown Cler: Parl.</signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>John Wright</hi> at the Kings head in the Olde-Baily, 1647.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:114517:2"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 68 -->
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:114517:2"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 68 -->
            <opener>
               <dateline>
                  <date>Die Sabbati, 28. Auguſt, 1647.</date>
               </dateline>
            </opener>
            <head>AN ORDINANCE FOR The reliefe of the diſtreſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed Proteſtants come out of <hi>IRELAND.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>HE Lords and Commmons Aſſembled in Parliament taking into conſideration the ſad and miſerable con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dition of divers diſtreſſed Proteſtants who have beene ſtripped of their Eſtates, and forced to flye from the
<pb facs="tcp:114517:3"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 69 -->
Kingdome of <hi>Ireland</hi> (by thoſe barbarous and bloudy Rebels) and doe now remaine about the Cities of <hi>London</hi> and <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> and places adjacent mentioned in the Weekely Bills of Mortality. Doe order, and ordaine, And be it hereby ordered and ordained that there be upon Tueſday the laſt of this preſent <hi>Auguſt,</hi> being the day of publique Thankſgiving for Gods great goodneſſe in giving ſo glorious a Victory over the bloudy Rebels by the Forces under the Command of Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lonell <hi>MICHAEL JONES</hi> in the Province of <hi>Lymſter</hi> in the Kingdome of <hi>Ireland,</hi> a Collection for the reliefe of the ſaid diſtreſſed Proteſtants in all Churches, and Chappells within the Cities of <hi>London</hi> and <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> and places adjacent men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned in the weekly Bills of mortality, and the moneyes ſo collected are to be paid in by the ſeverall Church-Wardens, or Collectors unto Mr. <hi>John Poacock, Willi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>am Greenhill, John Randall, and  <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                     <desc> _____ </desc>
                  </gap>  Hutchinſon.</hi> Treaſurers at Chriſt-Church <hi>London.</hi> And it is further ordered and or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dained
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:114517:3"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 69 -->
by the authority aforeſaid, That there be a Collection in all other Churches and Chappells within the Kingdome of England and Dominion of Wales upon Tueſday ſeven night next following being the day of publique thankſgiving for the blesſing aforeſaid. And the moneyes ſo col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lected, are to be paid in to the Sheriffes of every county reſpectively, who are ſpeedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly to pay in the ſame unto the Treaſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rers above mentioned, and are to receive an Acquintance from the ſaid Treaſurers ſigned under their hands, or the hands of any two of them, And the ſaid Treaſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rers are to iſſue out the money to ſuch diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>treſſed Proteſtants, and in ſuch ſummes as they ſhall receive warrant for, from ſuch Committee as ſhall be appointed by both Houſes of Parliament. And eſpeciall care is to be taken that ſuch onely have war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rants granted, who are reall Proteſtants, and have conſtantly oppoſed the horred Rebellion, who are to have Certificates or Certificates of their quality and Leſſes under the hands of three Perſons of good
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:114517:4"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 70 -->
quality at the leaſt, who have had publique employment under the Parliament within the Kingdome of Ireland. And it is likewiſe ordered and ordained, That ſuch warrant with an Acquit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tance under the hand of the party, or his or her Aſſignes that receive any ſumme; ſhall be a ſufficient diſcharge to the Treaſurers for any ſuch ſumme ſo paid and received. And laſtly it is or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dained that the Lord Major of the Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tie of <hi>London,</hi> and the Sheriffes of <hi>London</hi> and Middleſex doe ſend to each Church and Chappell within the Cities of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> and <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> and parts adjacent, expreſſed in the Weekly Bills of Mor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tality, one printed Coppy of this Ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nance, and the Knights and Burgeſſes ſerving in Parliament ſhall ſend into their reſpective Counties within the Kingdom of <hi>England</hi> and Dominion of <hi>VVales,</hi> ſuch number of printed Coppies to the She<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riffes of their Counties as ſhall be ſuffici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ent for every Church and Chappell, who is to diſpoſe them to every Chuch &amp; Chap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pel,
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:114517:4"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 70 -->
&amp; the Miniſters of every church &amp; chap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pell, are to publiſh or cauſe to be publiſhed this Ordinance in the Church or Chappell on the ſaid dayes, and are to exhort the people to contribute hereunto. And in caſe this Ordinance be not timely brought to any Miniſter ſo that it may be pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſhed as above-ſaid, then ſhall the Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſter the next Lords day after the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceipt of it publiſh or cauſe to be pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſhed the ſame in the Church or Chap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pell, and exhort the people to contri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bute to this ſo pious and charitable worke.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb n="4" facs="tcp:114517:5"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 71 -->
            <pb n="5" facs="tcp:114517:5"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 71 -->
            <pb facs="tcp:114517:6"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 72 -->
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
